（男）ハア ハア
I'm in deep shit. Seriously deep shit!
ヤバイ これは本気でヤバイ
Subaru? What's wrong?
（少女）
スバル どうかしたの？
Oh, I see. This is where they suck you in.
（ナツキ･スバル）
ああ なるほど　ここで引きね
No... Run away, now!
（男）
ダメだ 逃げろ 早く
ハア
Nah, not natto.
やっぱ 納豆はねえな
Just wait...
（男）待っていろ…
That'll be 363 yen.
（店員）363円です
Oh, a ridged 10-yen coin.
お… ギザ10
I...
（男）俺が―
will...
必ず―
お前を救ってみせる
save you!
I guess after spending all day
holed up in their room gaming,
まあ １日部屋に閉じこもって
ゲームやってりゃ―
anyone would start seeing things.
目も疲れるわな
What's going on?
どうなってんだ？
This stuff obviously isn't fake.
どう見ても 作り物じゃねえよな
Wait...
ってことは…
Does this mean that...
つまり これは ひょっとして―
I've been summoned into a different world!?
異世界召喚ってやつー？
（少女）ウッヒヒヒ
It's safe to assume that this is a fantasy world
ファンタジー異世界と仮定して
文明は お約束の中世風ってとこか
complete with the typical medieval culture.
A realm where demihumans are commonplace,
亜人ありありの世界観で
たぶん 戦争とか冒険ありあり
and probably stuff like wars
and adventures too.
And here, I'm...
そして この世界で俺は…
Hey!
Watch out!
All right! It's my time to shine!
きた 俺のターンきたー！
This must be the event
where I cast my first spell!
これは おそらく
初めての魔法発動イベント
ハアッ！
（騎士）危ない！
Look out!
（騎士）ハッハハハハ
（人々の歓声）
Way to go!
（男）よくやった！
Well done!
I guess I'm not ready to use magic yet.
魔法を使うには
ちょっと早かったな
（スバル）読めねえ
I can't read a thing.
（カドモン･リッシュ）
お兄ちゃん 変わった格好してるな
Hey, buddy.
Those are some weird clothes.
旅の途中か？
Are you a traveler?
これは…
What are these?
そいつは リンガだ
They're appas.
They understand me, though.
（スバル）
だが 言葉は通じる　問題は…
So the question is...
Huh? What kind of money is that?
あ？ どこの国の金だ？
んなもん ルグニカじゃ使えねえ
You can't use that junk in Lugunica.
So that means you're flat broke?
さては てめえ 一文無しだな？
あっち行け
商売のジャマすんじゃねえー！
Scram!
Quit interferin' with my business!
Whatever.
しかたねえ
I'll just try to gather some information for now.
ここは まず地道に情報収集か
This place is for demihumans only.
（店員）
ここは亜人専門店だ
（スバル）
イッテー ま… 前が…
Ow! My... eyes...
なんか話違わね？
Isn't this the wrong script?
Wasn't I summoned into a different world!?
異世界召喚じゃねえのかよ！
俺の主人公設定は
どこいったんだよ！
Where's my protagonist status!?
Damn it.
Phone Menu
Contacts
Group Search
Abbreviations
New Contacts
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
No
Signal
Pizza
Contacts
City Hall
No
Signal
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
City Hall
Pizza
No
Contacts
Dad
Mom
Signal
Pizza
No
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Dad
Mom
No
Signal
Contacts
City Hall
Pizza
No
Dad
Mom
No
Signal
Contacts
Dad
No
Signal
City Hall
Mom
Pizza
Dad
Contacts
No
Signal
Dad
Contacts
Mom
City Hall
Dad
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
Mom
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
Signal
No
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
Signal
Dad
Contacts
City Hall
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Dad
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
City Hall
Contacts
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
City Hall
Contacts
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
City Hall
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
Dad
City Hall
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
My cell phone still works.
携帯は無事か
Dad
Signal
No
Contacts
City Hall
Mom
Pizza
Signal
Dad
No
Signal
City Hall
No
Signal
Dad
Mom
Pizza
Contacts
No
Signal
City Hall
Dad
No
Signal
Pizza
Mom
Dad
Contacts
Signal
No
City Hall
Pizza
Signal
Mom
Dad
Pizza
City Hall
Mom
Contacts
Dad
Pizza
No
Signal
Pizza
No
Signal
Dad
City Hall
Mom
Signal
No
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
No
Signal
Contacts
City Hall
Dad
Mom
Pizza
Signal
No
Not that it's good for anything!
って 携帯持ってる意味ねえ！
And what kind of low-level starting gear is this?
だいたい 初期装備 貧弱すぎだろ
Spoon-feed me a bit more!
もうちょっと
福利厚生充実してないと―
We're called the entitled generation!
俺みたいな ゆとりは
納得できないよ！
エクスカリバーの１つも
持ってねえし！
I don't even have Excalibur or anything!
つーか そもそも召喚ものなら
俺を召喚した美少女どこよ？
And besides, if I was summoned here,
where's the cute girl who summoned me?
Did she summon me just to abandon me?
まさか召喚しておいて放置？
お… やっと来たか
俺のこと召喚した美少女…
Oh, is she finally here!?
The cute girl who summoned... me...
（カン）
てめえ 何 ブツブツ言ってんだ？
What are you rambling about?
（チン）
痛(いて)え思いしたくなきゃ―
If you don't wanna get hurt,
cough up whatever you've got!
出すもん出しな
Crap, it's a coercion event...
やっべ 強制イベント発生だ
（少女）
どけどけー！ そこの奴らー！
Move it, move it!
All of you!
Outta my way!
ジャマー！
Here we go!
きたー！ 今度こそ
召喚した美少女 本人か？
Is that the cute girl who summoned me!?
召喚？
Summoned?
I dunno what you're talkin' about, but I'm busy!
なんか知んねえけど
私 忙しいんだ
ごめんな！ 強く生きてくれ！
Sorry! Live strong!
Wait, what?
（スバル）
…って ええ？ ええ？
What!?
Hey, that didn't happen to make you
change your minds about this, did it?
（スバル）
今ので 毒気が抜かれて
気が変わったりしませんかね？
All it did was piss us off more.
（トン）
むしろ 水差されて気分を害した
Yeah, thought so.
ですよね
（スバル）
だが落ち着け ナツキ･スバル
Stay calm, Natsuki Subaru.
Since ancient times,
it's been a rule that anyone
古来より 異世界に招かれた人間は
超常の力を発揮するのが お約束
summoned into a different world
will awaken to supernatural powers!
I'll mow these guys down and use them
as stepping stones to my shining future!
バッタバッタ なぎ倒して
俺の輝かしい未来の糧にしてやる！
You lumps of EXP!
経験値どもめ！
That's the first time I've ever hit someone!
初めて 人殴った
思ったより こっちも痛い
I didn't expect it to hurt me that much.
But this world really is set up
so that I'll be strong!
だが やっぱり
この世界だと俺は強い設定か
アドレナリン ダバダバで
こりゃ もらったー！
My adrenaline is surging! I've got this!
I'm sorry! It was all my fault!
Forgive me! Spare me!
すいません
俺が全面的に悪かったです
許してください 命だけは…
So you wanna be funny, huh!? Die!
ふざけたマネしやがって この！
この！ この！
You're in for a world of pain!
楽に逝けると思うなよ！
That's enough.
（少女）そこまでよ
（チン）うっ
何だ？ てめえは！
Who the hell are you!?
If you do it now, I'll let it slide.
（少女）
今なら許してあげる
So kindly return what you stole from me.
だから 潔く盗んだものを返して
What we stole?
盗んだもの？
（少女）
お願い あれは大切なものなの
Now, please. It's important to me.
I'd give up on anything else,
but I can't let you have that.
ほかのものなら諦めもつくけど
あれだけは 絶対にダメ
So be good and hand it over.
いい子だから おとなしく渡して
こいつを助けに来たわけじゃ
ねえのか
You didn't come to save this kid?
What strange clothes.
（少女）
変な格好の人ね
私と関係あるのか聞かれたら
無関係って答えるしかないわ
If you asked me if I had any connection to him, then I'd have to say no.
Then you've got no business with us!
だったら 俺らは関係ねえ
何か盗まれたってなら
さっきのガキだ
If someone stole from you,
it was that brat who just ran by!
そうだ あっちだ
あっちに逃げてった
Yeah! Go that way!
She ran right past us!
うーん ウソじゃないみたい
It doesn't seem like they're lying.
I have to hurry!
早く追いかけないと
（少女）
でも それはそれとして―
But regardless of that...
I can't overlook what's going on here.
見過ごせる状況じゃないの
Magic?
（チン）
魔法… ふざけやがって
You little brat...
I don't care if you can use magic! I'll kill you!
魔法使いだろうが
何だろうが ぶっ殺す
２対１で勝てっと思ってんのか
ああ？
You think you can take on the both of us!?
I see your point.
The odds are against me.
そうね　２対１は不公平かも
How about we even the odds, then?
（パック）
じゃあ ２対２なら対等な条件かな
ニャ
Y-You're a spirit arts user?
（トン）
せ… 精霊術師か
Correct. Back off now and I won't go after you.
（女性）ご名答
今すぐ引き下がるなら追わないわ
すぐ決断して　急いでるの
Decide quickly. I'm in a hurry.
（チン）
クソアマ 次に会った時は
タダじゃおかねえからな！
You dirty bitch!
Next time I see you,
I'll make you regret this!
この子に何かしたら
末代までたたるよ
Do anything to her and you'll never live it down.
Not that you'd live much longer.
その場合 君が末代なんだけど
You're a lifesaver. Thanks.
助かった ありがとう
（女性）動かないで
Don't move.
See? You averted your eyes because
you have a guilty conscience!
ほら やましいことがあるから
目をそらしたんだ
私の目に 狂いはないみたいね
Looks like my judgment was spot-on.
Are you sure?
（パック）
どうかなあ 今のは
健全な男の子的反応ってだけで―
I think that's how any male would've reacted.
I didn't sense any malice behind it at all.
邪悪な感じはゼロだったけど
You be quiet, Puck.
パックは黙ってるの
あなた 私から徽章(きしょう)を
盗んだ子を知ってるでしょ
You know who stole my insignia, don't you?
Sorry, but I really don't have the slightest idea.
ああ いや 悪いけど―
全然 全く これっぽっちも知らない
えっ やだ ウソ
What? Wait, really?
Did I really just take a detour for nothing?
まさか ホントに
ただ回り道しちゃっただけ？
早く追いかけたほうがいいよ
お嬢さん
You should probably hurry after her, little missy.
I could help...
なんなら 手伝…
（パック）
あーあ 無理して立つから
どうしよっか？
Aww, you shouldn't have tried to get up.
What should we do?
It's none of our business.
関係ないでしょ
死ぬほどじゃないもの
He won't die. We'll just leave him.
放っておくわよ
（パック）ホントに？
Really?
ホントに
Yes, really.
You say that, but I bet you'll still help him.
（パック）
そんなこと言って
助けるんじゃない？
I will not!
（女性）助けない！
Yeah, right.
Absolutely not! I am not going to save him!
絶対の絶対
助けたりなんかしないんだから！
She's super cute even when she's mad.
（スバル）
怒った顔も すげえかわいいな
That's a fantasy world for you.
さすが異世界ファンタジー
Is this someone's lap?
これは ひざ枕？
You're awake?
（女性）目が覚めた？
I didn't know cute girls were this hairy.
なんか美少女って
思ったよりも毛深いんだね
Wait, that can't be right!
…って そんなわけあるか！
わあっ！
It's just a little something we did for you
so that you'd be comfortable until you woke up.
せめて 目が覚めるまで―
幸せに過ごさせてあげようという
粋な計らいだよ
Seriously, stop talking like that.
とりあえず その裏声やめて
No sane guy confuses a cat for the main heroine!
猫とヒロイン間違えるとか
ありえないから
Aww, making myself bigger was worth it to see you so happy.
いやあ こんなに喜ばれると―
僕も わざわざ
巨大化したかいがあるよ
I'm not happy!
喜んでねえし！ おっ…
Sorry about all this.
（スバル）
なんか悪かったな
You even stayed with me
while I was unconscious.
結局 目が覚めるまで
つきあってくれたみたいで
Don't get the wrong idea.
勘違いしないの
I only stayed because I wanted
to ask you a few things.
聞きたいことがあるから
しかたなく残っただけなんだから
Both healing your wounds and having
Puck be your pillow until you woke up
あなたの体の傷を
治してあげたのも―
目覚めるまで
パックを枕にさせてあげたのも―
were done for my own benefit.
私のためだったの
So I need you to repay me in kind.
だから その分に
応えてもらうんだから
You're making a big deal
out of such a normal favor.
恩着せがましい感じを演出しつつ
普通のお願いじゃね？
No such thing.
そんなことはない
You have some idea
who stole my insignia, right?
あなた 盗まれた徽章には
心当たりあるでしょう？
徽章？
Insignia?
You mean one of those badge things
that shows your allegiance?
徽章っていや 身分を表す
バッジみたいなもんだっけ
It has a jewel in the center,
真ん中に 宝石が
埋め込まれていて―
and it's about this big.
このくらいの大きさなんだけど
Sorry, but no matter how many
times you ask me, I have no idea.
ごめんだけど 何回聞かれても
心当たりはないかな
I see. That's fine.
そう それじゃ しかたないわね
But you gave me the information
that you know nothing
でも あなたは
何にも知らないって情報を―
私に教えてくれたわけだから―
in return for healing you,
so your debt's paid off.
ちゃんとケガを治した分の
話はしたものね
Huh?
Well, I'm in a hurry, so I'm going now.
じゃあ 急いでるから
もう行くわね
Your wounds should be better now,
ケガは 一とおり
治ってるはずだけど―
but next time, don't do something as dangerous as wandering into a deserted alley alone.
次からは 人けのない路地に
１人で入るなんて―
危ないことは
するべきじゃないわね
あっ これは心配じゃなくて忠告
I'm not concerned. I'm just warning you.
If that happens to you again,
saving you won't be of any benefit to me,
次に同じような場面に
出くわしても―
私があなたを助ける
メリットがないもの
so don't expect me to help.
だから 期待しちゃダメだからね
Sorry. She's so insincere.
ごめんね
素直じゃないんだよ うちの子
Don't take it the wrong way.
変に思わないであげて
Insincere?
素直じゃないって
そんなレベルじゃねえだろ
That's an understatement.
She's in such a hurry to find
what was stolen from her,
大切なもん盗まれて急いでんのに
俺のこと助けてくれて―
yet she stopped to help me.
And she even came up with that lame
excuse so I didn't feel like I owed her.
おまけに 見ず知らずの俺に
負い目を感じさせないように―
All for a total stranger.
下手くそすぎるフォローまでして
そんな生き方…
Anyone who lives like that...
is gonna end up wasting their whole life!
メチャクチャ
損するばっかじゃねえか
Hey! Wait up!
おーい 待ってくれよ
What? Just so you know, I can only
spend a little more time with you.
何？ 言っておくけど
これ以上は 私も―
ちょっとしか
つきあってあげられないから
I think you're being a little lenient...
若干 甘さみえてるけど
Forget that. You lost
something important, right?
あっ それより 大切なもんなんだろ
俺にも手伝わせてくれ
Let me help you.
But you said you don't know anything—
でも あなたは何も知らないって…
I remember her face. That's something!
ああ… 少なくとも顔は覚えてる
もう一度見れば分かる
I'll know if I see her again!
You're very strange.
変な人
Just so you know,
I can't do anything to thank you.
言っておくけど
何のお礼もできません
I don't need you to.
お礼なんていらない
俺が 君に礼をしたい
I want to help because
I'm trying to thank you.
だから手伝いたいんだ
I didn't do anything to earn your thanks.
お礼をされるようなことしてない
I told you that you've already paid me back for healing your wounds.
言ったでしょ 傷のことなら
ちゃんと対価はもらってるんだから
Okay, fine.
なら―
I'm going to help you for my own sake.
俺も俺のために 君を手伝う
My objective is... Let's see...
俺の目的は… そうだな
Yeah! One good deed per day!
うん 一日一善だ
I don't sense any malice.
I think you should accept his offer.
悪意は感じないし
素直に受け入れてもいいと思うよ
The more shields between yourself
and ruffians, the better, after all.
暴漢相手の弾避けは
多いほうがいいしね
That's all you want me around for!?
って そんな物騒な役割かよ
I mean it, though.
でも ホント
何のお礼もできないからね
I can't do anything to thank you.
No problem. Just leave it to me!
ああ 大丈夫　俺に任せとけ
I talked big, but isn't this city
too huge to find one little thing in?
（スバル）
でかい口 たたいちまったけど―
この街って 捜し物するには
広すぎねえ？
It's the capital of Lugunica.
ルグニカ王国の王都だもん
そんなことも知らなかったの？
You didn't even know that, um...
えっと…
That's right. We haven't exchanged names yet.
そういえば お互い
まだ名前も聞いてないよね？
自己紹介しておく？
Should we all introduce ourselves?
Oh, yeah, you're right.
そういや そうだな
I'll introduce myself first, then.
じゃ ここは俺から
名乗らせて頂こう
My name is Natsuki Subaru.
俺の名前は ナツキ･スバル
Not only am I clueless,
I'm also broke beyond compare!
無知蒙昧(むちもうまい)にして
天下不滅の無一文　よろしく
Nice to meet ya!
When that's all you say,
you really do sound hopeless.
（パック）
それだけ聞くと
もう 絶体絶命だよね うん
And I'm Puck! Nice to meet you!
そして 僕はパック
よろしくー
It's very unusual to see someone
touch a spirit so casually.
精霊と こんな気軽に
接する人なんて ホント珍しい
Where are you from?
どこから来たの？
Well, following the usual pattern,
a small island nation to the east.
まあ パターンからすると
東の小っさい島国だな
Lugunica is the easternmost
nation on our continental map.
ルグニカは 大陸図で見て
一番東の国だから―
There's no nation east of here.
この国より東なんてないけど
Wait, for real?
ウソ マジで？ 東の果て？
There's nothing east of here?
You have no idea where you are,
you have no money,
今 自分のいる場所が
分かってなくて―
お金も持ってなくて
字も読めなくて 頼れる人もいない
you can't read, and you
have no one you can rely on.
You might be in an even more
precarious position than me, um...
ひょっとすると 私より
危ない立場なんじゃ？
えっと… スバルって
Subaru, was it?
お？ おお… イエス 俺の名前
Yes, that's my name.
You know, now that I take a closer look,
you're pretty well-built.
でも こうして見ると
結構 体鍛えてるみたいだね
I do work out every day.
毎日 筋トレだけはね
When you're a twixter who's gotta guard
his house, that's the least you can do.
まっ 自宅の守人
引きこもりとしては―
そんぐらいは当然ってもんだ
I'm not sure I understand what a "twixter" is,
その 引きこもりっていうのは
よく分からないんだけど―
but basically, you're from
a respectable family, right?
スバルって
かなりいい家柄の出でしょ？
H-Hey—
Your fingers show that too.
They're very pretty.
（女性）
この指もそうだけど とてもきれい
They're evidence that you don't
live like a peasant at all.
庶民とは
暮らしが違いすぎる手だもの
And your muscles don't look like
the kind you gain from working.
筋肉のつき方も
仕事でついた感じじゃないし
S-So anyway, I know your cat's name now,
あっ そういえば
飼い猫の名前は聞いたけど―
but I haven't heard yours yet.
君の名前は聞いてなかったな
My name?
（女性）私の名前？
（スバル）うん そう
Yeah.
I'm...
私は…
Satella.
サテラ
I have no family name.
家名はないの
サテラと そう呼ぶといいわ
You can just call me Satella.
I see.
そうか　サテラか
Satella, huh?
That's a nice name.
いい名前だ
ハア… 趣味が悪いよ
You have terrible taste.
Okay, time to get back to asking around!
んじゃ 聞き込み再開といこうぜ！
Hey, Subaru...
（サテラ）ねえ スバル
あの子 迷子になってる
気がしない？
Don't you get the feeling that she's lost?
I mean, yeah, but what about our questioning?
（スバル）
いや だから聞き込みは…
That's important too, but if she's lost,
we have to do something.
それも大事だけど 迷子だったら
なんとかしてあげないと
I'm in no place to talk after you saved me,
助けられた俺が言うのも
なんだけど―
but do you understand the position we're in?
今の置かれてる状況とか
分かってる？
でも…
But...
She's crying!
あの子は今 泣いている
そうでしょう スバル
Can't you see that, Subaru?
If you can't do this with me, that's fine.
つきあいきれないって言うなら
それでもいい
Thanks for all your help, Subaru.
ここまでありがとう スバル
I'll handle it on my own from here.
あとは自分でなんとかしてみるから
あの子 どうにかしてあげてから
After I help that little girl.
I'm sorry I'm not who you were looking for.
捜してた相手じゃなくて ごめんね
So what's the matter?
ねえ どうしたの？
Aren't your mom and dad with you?
お父さんかお母さんは？
一緒じゃないの？
H-Hey... Don't cry.
えっと その… 泣かないで
I won't do anything to you, okay?
お姉ちゃんは あなたに
何もしたりしないから
What I have here is one ridged 10-yen coin.
（スバル）
ここに取り出しましたるは
１枚のギザ10にございます
I will now clutch it tightly in my hand.
さーて これをぎゅっと手で
握りつぶしてやります
One, two, three, and...
グッグッグッとな
Wow, imagine that!
すると あら不思議
Now let's see where that coin was hiding.
はい 消えたコインは
こんなところにおりました
You can keep it.
プレゼントしてあげよう
貴重品だから大事にしてね
It's rare, so don't lose it.
はあ！ ありがとう
Thank you!
I see. You got separated from your mom, huh?
（スバル）
そっか お母さんと
はぐれちまったのか
Hey, it'll be fine.
なに 大丈夫 大丈夫
Just leave it to the two of us.
お兄ちゃんとお姉ちゃんに
任せとけって
We'll find her for you in no time.
すぐに バシッと
見つけてあげっからな
When we do this,
こうしてると―
people who don't know us probably think we're a married couple and child, huh?
何も知らない人たちからは―
若夫婦と その子供みたいに
見える気がしない？
How embarrassing.
照れるな
At the very best, I can only
see you as her older brother.
（サテラ）
ひいき目に見ても―
スバルと この子が
兄妹(きょうだい)にしか見えないと思うけど
What makes you think
I'm so much younger than you!?
何で俺が そんな年下？
Oh, mommy!
Mommy!
Looks like she found her.
見つかったみてえだな
Yeah. I'm glad.
うん よかった
So...
（スバル）それで？
I think we just wasted a bunch of time,
だいぶ遠回りに
なっちゃった気がすっけど
but what benefit will you
insist we got out of this?
そこんとこ お姉さん的には―
どんなメリットがあったんだと
主張するんでしょうか
That's easy. Now we can continue
our search with our minds at ease, right?
簡単よ
これで 私たちは気持ちよく
捜し物の続きができるでしょ
Anyway, why did you help me?
それより どうして
手伝ってくれたの？
You were against the idea.
スバル反対してたのに
I could say I just wanted to
show off my magic trick,
（スバル）
手品を見せびらかしたかった
ってーと ウソになるね
but that'd be a lie.
Remember? I'm helping you find your
insignia as my good deed of the day.
言ったろ？
君の徽章捜しを手伝って
俺は一日一善
But since you helped that little girl,
isn't your one good deed over with?
（サテラ）
じゃあ 女の子を助けて
あげられたから―
もう一善は 済んだんじゃない？
There's no holes in that comeback!
正論すぎる切り返し
Come on, it doesn't hurt to do more than
one nice thing in a day, right?
いや ほら いいことは
一日何回やってもいいじゃん？
I just got tomorrow's out of the way.
明日の分の前倒しだよ
My plan is to get a week's worth
of good deeds taken care of early!
今週のノルマを
先に消化しちゃう腹積もりだよ
Subaru, you're the type that basically
wastes your whole life, aren't you?
スバルって すごーく
損する性格してるのね
You're the last person I want to hear that from.
ほかの誰でもなく
君にだけは言われたくねえな
You're not a bad kid, though.
悪い子じゃないのよね
Why are you treating me like
I'm younger than you again?
だから 何で年下扱い？
I doubt there's too many years between us.
俺と君って そこまで
年の差ないと思うぜ
I don't think you'll get anywhere guessing that.
その予想 当てにならないと思う
I'm a half-elf.
私 ハーフエルフだから
なるほどな
Now I get it.
No wonder I thought you were so cute!
どうりで かわいいと思った
Elves are always beautiful, right?
エルフは美人ってのは
お約束だもんな
What?
どったの？
Didn't you hear me?
どうしたのっていうか
あの ほら 私 ハーフエルフ…
I said I'm a half-elf.
Yeah, I heard you.
聞いたよ
てい！
What'd you do that for?
…って 急に何すんの
I just had to do something about
this unbearable tingle I'm feeling!
なんとなく 耐えがたい
ムズムズ感を形にしたくて
I can't accept being hit for a reason like that.
そんな理由じゃ 殴られた側は
納得いかねえよ
Though I'll forgive you because you're so soft.
プニプニだったから許すけど
I didn't hit you out of anger or anything.
僕も別に怒って
たたいたわけじゃないよ
The opposite, in fact.
どちらかっていうと 逆だね
Subaru, you're such a dunderhead!
もう スバルのおたんこなす
Dunderhead?
“おたんこなす”って
きょうび聞かねえな
Who says that nowadays?
And why are you insulting me?
そして なぜに俺は
罵倒されてるの？
Hmph! Whatever!
フンだ　知らない
More importantly, we have to
get back to the search.
それより捜し物の続き 始めなきゃ
Hey, hang on!
ああ 待てって
Running around aimlessly never ends well.
ノープランで動き回っても
いい結果はついてこない
There's a basic rule of searches.
ここは捜査の基本だ
A basic rule of searches?
捜査の基本？
Yep. You revisit the crime
scene a hundred times.
そう 現場100回ってやつ
Where was your insignia stolen?
その徽章は
どこら辺で盗まれたんだ？
So you see, it seems the crime
happened right around here,
そんなわけで どうやら現場は
この辺りだったらしく―
so I came back to this fruit stand
after valiantly telling her to leave it all to me.
俺に任せろと 勇ましく宣言して
戻ってまいりました 果物屋
You again?
何だ？ 客かと思ったら
またお前かよ 一文無し
I thought I had a customer,
but it's just the broke kid.
Do you really want to take that attitude?
（スバル）
いいのかよ そんな態度で
Haven't you noticed
something different about me?
さっきの俺と違うことに
気づかないのかい？
Like what?
（カドモン）何？
Just look who I brought with me!
どうだ 連れだぜ 連れ
I brought someone who just
might become a regular!
お得意様候補を
連れてきてやったんだぜ
Um, Subaru...
（サテラ）
あの スバル
変に期待してくれてるんだけど―
You seem to have some
weird expectations of me,
but I don't have any money either.
私もお金 持ってないわよ
Huh!? Seriously?
（スバル）
でっ… あれ？ マジで
So now that I've got two broke customers,
what did you want to say to me, bud?
で… 無一文が
２人になっただけの状況で―
何が言いたかったんだ？ 兄ちゃん
We're actually looking for someone,
実は 人を捜してたんだけど―
and we were hoping you could
answer a few questions...
ちょっと お話
聞かせてもらえないかなー 的な…
It's called sarcasm!
I have no time for dirt-poor losers!
文無しにつきあってらんねえって
皮肉言ってんだよ！
Get outta here!
帰った 帰った！
Mister!
（子供）お兄ちゃん
Thanks for your help earlier.
（母親）先ほどは どうも
What brings you here?
（スバル）
何でまた こんなところに
It's my husband's shop,
so we were just stopping by.
主人のお店なので
ちょっと立ち寄ったんですよ
Husband?
主人？
Hey, attagirl.
Wait, you know these broke losers?
それより お前
この文無し２人と知り合いか？
Our little girl got lost
and they helped her find me.
この子が迷子になったのを
見つけてくれたんですよ
Pretty lady, here!
お姉ちゃん はい
Please accept it.
もらってあげてください
She's trying to thank you in her own way.
娘なりに お礼がしたいと
思ってるみたいなので
Thank you.
ありがとう
Sorry about that.
すまなかったな
You helped my daughter,
and I want to thank you.
娘の恩人だ 礼がしたい
何でも聞いてくれ
You can ask me anything.
There, you see?
ほらね ちゃんと巡り巡って
私たちのためになったじゃない
It came back around
and worked in our favor!
The air, the atmosphere,
空気と雰囲気と―
and most likely the attitudes of the people living here are awful.
あと たぶん
住んでる人間の性格も悪そう
本当に ここにいるのか？
Is she really here?
It might be that Felt girl.
ひょっとして フェルトの奴かも
しれねえなあ
You said a nimble little blond girl, right?
金髪のはしっこい小娘だろ？
She's well-known in the slums.
貧民街じゃ有名だ
住んでる場所までは知らねえがな
Dunno where she lives, though.
Maybe someone will tell us if we ask.
（サテラ）
聞けば教えてくれるかしら？
No one wants to sell out one of their own,
so I don't think that would work.
（パック）
誰も 自分たちの仲間を
売ったりしないから―
聞いてもムダだと思うけど
Maybe we should come back later.
出直したほうが賢明か
Whether you stay or leave,
you should decide quickly.
進むにしても 戻るにしても
決断は早めにね
I'm almost out of time.
僕は そろそろ時間切れだ
Out of time? What's that mean?
何それ 時間切れ？
As cute as I look, I'm still a spirit.
僕は こんなかわいい見た目だけど
精霊だからね
It takes a lot of mana to maintain a physical form.
表に出てるだけで
結構マナを使っちゃうんだ
だから夜は
依り代の結晶石に戻って―
So at night, I return to the crystal
I was summoned from,
お天道様が出てる間に
備えてるんだよ
and prepare for the emergence of the sun.
まあ 平均的には
９時から５時が理想かな
I usually try to keep myself here
from about nine to five.
Nine to five? You sound like a civil servant.
９時５時とか 公務員みてえだな
精霊の雇用形態も 案外シビア…
Employment terms for spirits
are harsher than I thought.
We'll be fine without Puck.
パックがいなくても大丈夫
ここは進むしかない
We have to keep going.
I thought you'd say that.
だよね　でも ごめん
僕 もう限界だ
But sorry. I'm at my limit.
It almost looks like he's dying.
なんか 死にそうな消え方すんだな
Sorry to work you so hard, Puck.
無理させてごめんね パック
We'll take it from here, so get some rest.
あとは私たちで頑張るから
ゆっくり休んで
Don't do anything reckless.
くれぐれも ムチャしないように
If it comes down to it, use your odo to summon me again.
いざとなったら オドを使って
僕を呼び出すんだよ
Okay, take care of the rest, Subaru.
それじゃ あとは頼んだよ スバル
Come to think of it, I haven't been alone with a girl since I was in grade school!
おいおい 女の子と２人きりなんて
小学生以来のシチュエーションだ
Don't get any weird ideas.
変なこと考えちゃダメだからね
魔法は使えるんだから
I can use magic.
I won't!
考えねえよ
The bigger issue is how we should find Felt now.
それより ここからどうやって
フェルトを見つけ出すかだ
I'll ask the lesser spirits.
（サテラ）
微精霊に聞いてみる
Lesser spirits?
（スバル）微精霊？
Lesser spirits are beings
that haven't become spirits yet.
（サテラ）
微精霊っていうのは
まだ 精霊になる前の存在のこと
They grow over time, and when they gain
the strength and self-awareness,
時間がたって成長して
力と自意識が芽生えると―
they become full spirits, like Puck.
パックみたいな
立派な精霊になるの
It's getting more and more desolate.
（サテラ）
どんどん さみしくなってくる
Does she really live in a place like this?
ホントに
こんなとこに住んでるのか？
The lesser spirits said they saw someone
who looked like Felt going in this direction.
微精霊は こっちの方角に―
フェルトに似た人が入っていくのを
見たって言ってたんだけど
Hey, bro!
よう 兄弟
Does a girl named Felt live up this way?
この先 フェルトって子の
家で合ってる？
（男）
ああ？ フェルト？
Felt?
Nothing that way but Old Man Rom's loot house.
この先にあるのは
ロム爺(じい)の盗品蔵だけだ
ははん さては兄ちゃんたち
フェルトに何か盗まれたか
Did Felt steal something from you guys?
Well, good luck trying to negotiate it back.
まっ うまく交渉して
買い戻すんだな
強く生きろよ
Live strong.
Why do I have to pay to get back
something that was stolen from me?
（サテラ）
盗まれた物を返してもらうのに―
どうして
お金払わきゃいけないのかしら
（スバル）
まあ とにかく ここは
俺に任せてくれ
Well, anyway, let me handle this.
なんとか交渉してみる
I'll do the talking.
分かった　スバルに任せてみる
Okay. I'll let you handle it.
I thought you'd put up more of a fight.
やけに素直に任せたな
Going off how you've been up to now,
今までの流れだと―
"Someone as useless as you will handle this?"
“あなたみたいな
役立たずに任せる？―”
“へそで茶が湧いて
鼻が大爆笑しちゃうわー”
"That's too funny! I can't feel my sides!"
And I'd be hurt, but still make up
my mind to help you anyway.
的な発言に 俺が傷つきつつも
決意を新たにする展開だぜ
I wouldn't say something that mean.
そんなひどいこと 私 言わないわよ
Of course, I'd be lying if I said
you haven't been holding me back...
確かに―
スバルに足を引っ張られてないって
言ったら―
ウソになっちゃうけど
Did you really have to say that!?
ウソになっちゃうのかよ！
But...
でも―
I'll try believing in you.
スバルを信じてみる
It'll be a bonus if it actually goes well.
うまくいったら
もうけものぐらいの気持ちで
If you looked up at me and said,
そこは 上目遣いで―
"Do your best for me!"
“私のために頑張って”
ぐらい言ったほうが やる気でるぜ
I'd feel a lot more motivated.
I can't force myself
to say something like that.
そんな無理になんて言えないもの
But still...
でも 頑張って
Good luck.
Yeah, thanks.
うん 頑張る
I'll go in first.
You stay outside and keep watch.
俺が先に入るから
君は外 見張ってて
帰りは遅くならないけど
先に ご飯食べてていいよ
I won't be out too late,
but you can have dinner without me.
Don't say silly things like that.
バカなこと言ってないの
気をつけてね
Be careful.
Sure, sure.
Don't come in until I say it's safe, Satella.
サテラも 俺が声かけるまで
入ったらダメだぜ
どったの？
What?
N-No. It's nothing.
うっ… ううん　なんでもないの
I'll apologize if you get my insignia back.
徽章を取り戻せたら
ちゃんと謝るから
Excuse me...
おじゃましまーす
Now, am I walking into
a demon nest or a snake pit?
さて 鬼が出るか蛇(じゃ)が出るか
In a fantasy world,
either one is totally plausible...
ファンタジーだと
どっちも冗談じゃ済まねえな
This is all stolen loot?
これ全部 盗品かよ
つか 何で誰もいねえんだ？
And why isn't there anyone here?
A place that deals with stolen
goods can only be so careless.
盗品扱ってて
不用心にも程があるだろ
（女性）
ああ 見つけてしまったのね
Oh, dear, you found that?
Well, wrong place, wrong time.
それじゃしかたない
ええ しかたないのよ
Yes, just the wrong place at the wrong time.
Ow, that burns...
Oh, crap... Is all of this my blood?
（スバル）
やべえ これ全部 俺の血かよ
I'm in deep shit. Seriously deep shit!
ヤバイ これは本気でヤバイ！
Subaru? What's wrong?
（サテラ）
スバル？ どうかしたの？ スバル？
Subaru?
No... Run away, now!
ダメだ 逃げろ 早く
（スバル）…ていろ
Just wait...
I...
俺が 必ず―
will...
save you!
お前を救ってみせ…
What's the matter, bud?
どうしたよ 兄ちゃん
急に ほうけたツラして
You look like you saw a ghost.
What?
I asked you about the appa. The appa!
だからリンガだよ リンガ
兄ちゃん 金は持ってるのか？
Do you even have money?
What?
ハア？
Don't "what" me! The appa!
“ハア？”じゃねえよ リンガ！
買うのか？ 買わねえのか？
Are you buying it or not?
Oh, no, like I said,
ああ いや だから 俺
天魔不滅の一文無しだって…
I'm broke beyond compare.
The hell? If you're just
browsing, then move along.
…っだよ
ただの冷やかしなら 行った行った
I'm running a business here!
こっちは商売してんだ
冷やかしにはつきあってられん！
I have no time for window-shoppers!
どういうこと？
What's going on?
Wasn't it dark just a few minutes ago?
さっきまで 夜だったよな
腹の傷 ねえな
The wound on my belly is gone...
Oh, right! Satella!
あっ そうだ サテラ
Man, and Puck was counting
on me to take care of her.
サテラを頼むって パックに
言われたんじゃねえのかよ 俺
I have to get back to that shop!
とにかく あの店に戻らねえと
Hey, why do you look so spooked?
おいおい
ほうけたツラしてどうしたよ？
If you don't wanna get hurt,
cough up whatever you've got!
痛え思いしたくなきゃ
出すもん 出しな
You guys again? Did you see I was alone and decide to get revenge?
お前ら 俺が１人とみて
さっきの仕返しか？
Huh?
ああ？ 何 言ってんだ お前
The hell are you on about?
Are you nuts?
頭おかしいんじゃねえのか
いいさ兄ちゃん
とりあえず持ち物 全部置いてけ
Don't worry about it.
Just leave everything you've got
on the ground and we'll let you go.
それで勘弁してやっから
ああ はいはい 持ち物全部ね
Okay, fine. Everything I've got, huh?
Whatever. I don't have time for this.
急いでっからそれでいいや ホント
あと犬のマネな
Now act like a dog.
Get on all fours like a dog
and howl, "Help me!"
四つんばいで 犬のマネして
助けてくださいーって鳴けよ
Don't get ahead of yourselves, assholes!
（スバル）
調子乗んなや こらー！
どりゃー！
Whoa, there.
おっと
不登校児の有り余った時間
ナメんな
Don't underestimate a truant
kid with too much free time.
After swinging a wooden sword
around all the time for no reason,
日々 特に理由もなく
木刀振って鍛えた 俺の握力―
70キロオーバーだぞ！
my grip strength is over 70 kilograms!
I don't have time for your shit!
こっちは急いでんだ
二度とジャマすんじゃねえ！
Stay the hell out of my way!
Just keep it together.
Stay calm, you can do this!
ビビんな ビビんな ビビんなよ 俺
Am I stupid?
（スバル）バカか 俺は
After coming this far,
I can't leave without answers!
ここまできて 答えを見ないで
帰れるもんかよ
Is anyone there?
誰か いますか
Hello? Someone's in there, right!?
誰か… 誰かいるんだろ
頼むよ 返事してくれ 頼む…
Please, answer me! Please!
Shut yer trap!
（ロム爺）
じゃっかましいわい！
合図と合言葉も知らんで
扉をぶっ壊す気か
You tryin' to bust my door down when you don't even know the signal or password!?
You're...
あんた…
What're you all fidgety for?
（ロム爺）
なんじゃ さっきから
モジモジしおって
Are your balls chafin' ya that much?
キンタマの位置が
そんなに気になるか？
I'm not worried about
the position of my privates!
息子のポジション
気にしてるわけじゃねえよ
つーか シモから話に入るな
And don't start a conversation with a dirty joke!
You're already interrupting my evening booze.
人の晩酌のジャマしおって
You'll kill me if you start talkin'
about boring stuff now.
これで つまらん用事なら
ひどいぞい
Don't drink while the sun's
still up. You'll die young.
日のあるうちから
飲んでんじゃねえよ
早死にするぞ
Actually, this is a dumb question, but...
あっ つか… バカげた話なんだが…
Have you died recently?
爺さん 最近死んだことないか？
アハーハハハハ！
Well, I admit I'm an old man at death's door,
確かに死にかけの
ジジイなのは認めるが―
あいにくと 死んだ経験は
まだないぞ
but I ain't really died yet.
あっ じゃあ
銀髪の女の子を見なかったか
Okay, then have you seen
a girl with silver hair?
銀髪？
Silver hair?
I ain't seen anyone that eye-catching.
ああ そんな悪目立ちするもんは
見とらん
Was it all a dream?
（スバル）
全部 夢だってのか？
Then exactly how much of it was a dream,
だったら どっから
どこまでが夢で―
and why am I in this world?
俺は どうして
こんな世界にいるんだよ
So what are you doin' here anyway?
で… お前さんは
一体 何の用でここに来た？
Oh, I'm looking for an insignia.
ああ 俺は徽章を捜してる
It belongs to a silver-haired
girl who helped me out.
俺を助けてくれた
銀髪美少女の持ちもんだ
I don't know why, but it's important to her.
理由は知らんけど
大切なもんなんだと
I think she said it had a jewel in the center.
確か 真ん中に宝石が
はめ込まれてるって言ってた
An insignia with a jewel...
宝石が入った徽章…
悪いが そんな品物は
持ち込まれておらんぞ
Sorry, but I ain't got anything like that.
Are you sure? Try to think!
ホントにか？ よく思い出せよ
ボケてんじゃねえのか？
ガタがきて
Maybe you're just old and senile?
If I can't remember when
I'm at my best, with booze in me,
酒が入った 絶好調の今で
思い出せんなら―
the only explanation is that I don't know.
知らんとしか言えんな
But...
じゃが―
I've got someone bringing in some goods later.
今日は このあと
持ち込みの約束があってな
I'm told it's some fine loot.
前もって 上物と聞かされとる
There's a good chance it could
be what you're lookin' fer.
お前さんの捜し物の可能性は
十分あるじゃろな
Is a girl named Felt bringing it in?
持ち込むのは ひょっとして
フェルトって子が？
What, you even know who swiped it?
なんじゃ 盗った相手の名前まで
分かっとるのか
Of course, whether you'll be able to
afford it is another matter.
じゃが お前さんが
それを買い取れるかどうかは―
また別の話じゃぞ
It's no use trying to size me up.
ハッ いくら足元見てもムダだぜ
I'm as broke as they come, after all.
なにせ 俺は万夫不当の一文無し
Ain't no use talkin' about it, then.
話にならんじゃろうが
That's not true.
I can always try trading something.
いいや この世には
物々交換って手がある
Now that you say it,
you've got some unusual stuff there.
そういえば お前さん
何やら珍しいもの持っとるの
That's right.
（スバル）
おうよ 例えば―
For example, this is a corn potage snack.
これは コンポタスナック
超うめえんだぞ
It's super tasty!
That's food?
（ロム爺）食い物か
I see! What an odd flavor!
なるほど 不思議な味
酒にも合う うましうまし
These would go great with booze!
Right? Right?
そうだろ そうだろ
…って 勝手に食ってんじゃねえ！
Hey! Don't just start eating them!
Well, I dunno what you plan to trade,
まあ 何と交換するつもりか
知らんが―
but you'll have to come back
after Felt gets here.
フェルトが来てから
出直してくるんじゃな
Mm, that's good!
I guess there's those with money
and those without it in any world.
どこの世界でも 金のある奴と
ない奴がいるってことか
Still, the difference here is clear as day.
にしても 分かりやすいよな
（フェルト）
兄ちゃん 何やってんだ？
ジャマなんだけど
Hey, what're you doing there?
You're in my way.
Felt!
（スバル）フェルト
You know me?
私のこと 知ってんのか？
（スバル）知ってるも何も
お前を待ってたんだ
Of course I do! I've been waiting for you!
何のために
What for?
Wait, are you saying you don't remember me?
っていうか お前ってば―
俺のこと ひょっとして
覚えてないか？
うん… どっかで会った…
Have we met?
You know, I'm a busy girl,
so I don't remember most people
でも かなり衝撃的な
出会い方してねえと―
I meet unless they leave a huge impression.
私 暇じゃねえから
覚えてねえよ
That was pretty huge if you ask me, but...
衝撃的っちゃ 衝撃的だったが…
まあ それはいい
Well, forget it.
お前の持ってる徽章のことで
交渉がしたい
I want to negotiate for the insignia you have.
Oh, so that's it, huh?
なんだ そういうことか
だったら話は聞くぜ
All right, I'll hear you out.
For a rat...
（ロム爺）大ネズミに
（フェルト）毒
Poison.
For the White Whale...
（ロム爺）白鯨に
（フェルト）釣り針
A harpoon.
To the noble dragon, we are...
（ロム爺）我らが尊きドラゴン様に
（フェルト）クソッタレ
Shitbags.
待たせちまったな ロム爺
Sorry it took so long, Old Man Rom.
My target was pretty stubborn.
意外としつこい相手でさ
まくの手間取っちまった
It took awhile to shake them off.
Hey, Old Man Rom,
did you water down this milk?
おい ロム爺 このミルク
水入れて薄めてねえだろうな
It's nasty.
まずいぞ
C'mon, I give you something outta
the goodness of my heart, and you call it gross?
ったく もう…
人が好意で
出してやっとるもんを―
まずいまずいと
You two are closer than
I had either hoped or expected.
なんか 予想と期待以上に
親しげだな お前ら
I'm feeling left out over here.
置いてけぼりでさみしい
Don't talk like a wuss when you've got
a face almost as scary as Old Man Rom's.
ロム爺と
いい勝負の凶悪なツラして―
女々しいこと言ってんじゃねえよ
People have said a lot of things about me,
今まで いろんなこと
言われてきたけど―
but you think I can compete
with that ugly mug!?
このジジイと いい勝負させるか？
Okay, I went too far that time.
あ… さすがに今のは
言い過ぎたって
Sorry, bro.
悪かったよ 兄ちゃん
お前さんら ２人で結託して―
You two aren't banding together to try and piss me off, are you?
わしを怒らせに
来たんじゃなかろうな
Okay, well, how about we
get down to business?
じゃあ まあ改めて
本題に入るとすっか
What are you willing to pay?
兄ちゃん いくら出すんだ？
You don't waste any time.
って いきなりだな
Before I answer that,
you do have the insignia, right?
その前に 徽章はホントに
持ってるんだろうな？
たりめえだろ
Of course I do.
ほらよ
See?
（ロム爺）フン…
This one's got a jewel in it,
こっちは 宝石付きの代物だ
so I had to work pretty hard to get it.
しかも それなりに
苦労して手に入れた
If you can pay enough to match
my effort, we'll both be happy.
それに見合う額なら
お互いうれしいよな
金は ねえ
I have no money.
だったら話にならねえだろ！
Then we have nothing to discuss!
チッチッチッ　金はねえが
金に換えられるものがあるんだよ
Sure, I don't have money,
but I do have things worth money.
What I have here is a magical device
that can stop time for everyone, everywhere:
ここに取り出しましたるは
万物の時間を凍結させる魔機―
a cell phone!
携帯だ
What's that?
（フェルト）なんだこりゃ
Never seen one of those before.
（ロム爺）初めて見るな
くらえ 秒間９発 連続撮影
Take this!
Nine shots per second: Continuous Shot!
Whoa! Hey! What's that sound!? And that's way too bright!
何の音？
もう まぶしいっつうの
Are you tryin' to kill me!?
貴様！ わしを殺す気か
Don't you go makin' light of this old man
with dodgy tricks like that!
怪しげなマネしおって
ジジイをナメるでないぞ
Now hold on.
（スバル）待て待て
Is this...
これって…
Them's me and Felt's faces.
（ロム爺）
わしとフェルトの顔じゃな
どういう手品じゃ？
What sort of magic is that?
Weren't you listening?
（スバル）言ったろ
これは時間を切り取って
凍結させる 不思議なアイテム
This is a mystical item that
can freeze a moment in time.
With this, you can capture moments in time and store them forever.
この道具で あんたら２人の
時間を切り取って―
この中に閉じ込めたってわけさ
I see! That is amazing!
（フェルト）
なるほど そりゃすげえな
Never seen the like.
（ロム爺）初めて見るが…
これがウワサに聞く
ミーティアというやつかの？
Is that one of them metia
I've been hearing about lately?
"Metia"?
ミーティア？
It's the name for devices that let people who haven't
opened the gate use magic, like real magic users.
魔法使いのように
ゲートの開いてない者でも―
魔法が使えるようにできるという
道具の総称じゃ
Just tell me what it's worth.
この ミーティアは
売ったらどんなもんよ
What can I get for this metia thing?
Well, it's my first time dealing with a metia too,
さすがのわしも ミーティアなんぞ
扱うのは初めてじゃ
だが この徽章より―
but I'd say there's no doubt
that it'll fetch more than that insignia.
高値が付くことには
間違いないじゃろう
Then that settles it!
なら 決まりだ
この携帯と徽章を交換
This cell phone for the insignia!
Negotiations complete!
はい 交渉成立
ああっと
Hey!
Nope. Not yet.
いいや まだだ
Why not!?
（スバル）なんでだよ
You're not the only one
I'm negotiating with for this.
私の交渉相手は
兄ちゃんだけじゃないってこと
Huh?
Besides, I only nabbed this insignia
because I was asked to.
そもそも 私が この徽章を
ぎってきたのは―
頼まれたからなんだよ
My client told me I could
get ten holy coins for it.
これ１個で 聖金貨10枚と
引きかえるって話でな
You already had a deal when you stole it?
盗みの依頼が先約かよ
I don't know what the value
of ten holy coins is, but...
聖金貨10枚って相場が
いまいち分かんねえけど
That metia you've got is worth
at least twenty holy coins.
（ロム爺）
お前さんが持ってきた
ミーティアなら―
最低でも聖金貨20枚 いや…
No, there are probably fanciers out there who'd pay more for a thing like that.
それだけの物なら
もっと出す好事家もおるじゃろう
Really!? That means I can get away
with overcharging for it!
（フェルト）
マジか そりゃ
吹っかけがいがあるってもんだぜ
So when and where
are you meeting your client?
んで その依頼人とは
いつ どこで会う？
Don't worry. Negotiations will be held here.
心配すんな 交渉場所はここだ
私みたいな か弱いのが
１人で相手して―
If a little thing like me dealt with them alone,
踏み倒されたりしたら
かなわねえ
I'd be sunk if a client decided to bilk on me.
その点 ロム爺がいれば
安心だかんな フフッ
But I don't have to worry
with Old Man Rom here.
Do they know the password?
符丁は？
Oh, I didn't mention it.
（フェルト）教えてねえよ
たぶん 私の客だし
見てくるわ
That's probably for me. I'll go check.
You're okay with letting
her use you like that?
（スバル）
いいのかよ
あんな勝手ばっかさせて
Well, it ain't like we're total strangers.
まあ 知らん仲じゃないしのう
つきあいも短くない
I've known her a long time,
so I don't mind helpin' her out.
（ロム爺）
頼られてやるとするわい
You know, even I have to
give a wry chuckle at the sight
つーか
その文明人とは思えない姿に―
of someone looking like such a barbarian.
さすがのスバルくんも苦笑い…
Look where we are.
こんな場所じゃ どいつもこいつも
自分が生きるのに必死でな
Everyone around here
is desperate just to survive.
It's common for youngsters
to join forces with others
幼子が生きていくには―
似た境遇の子らと 徒党を
組んだりするのが常なんじゃが―
in similar situations to
keep themselves alive.
But Felt ain't cut out for that.
フェルトは それに向かん
なので わしがフェルトを
守ってやらねばならん
That's why I gotta look out for her.
I was right. It was for me.
（フェルト）
やっぱり 私の客だったよ
Over here. Care to sit down?
こっちだ　座るかい？
There seem to be several outsiders here.
（エルザ･グランヒルテ）
部外者が多い気がするのだけれど
（フェルト）
踏み倒されたら困るかんな
私ら 弱者なりの知恵だよ
Well, I'd be in trouble if you bilked on me.
We weaklings have our own brand of smarts.
I know this older fellow,
but who's the young man?
（エルザ）
そちらのご老人は分かるのだけれど
こちらのお兄さんは？
This guy's your rival.
この兄ちゃんは あんたのライバル
He's the other person negotiating with me.
私の もう１人の交渉相手さ
なるほど
I see.
I understand the situation now.
事情は飲み込めたわ
So that means you two will be
bidding against each other.
まっ そんなわけで
値段のつり上げ交渉ってわけだ
I don't really care who gets the insignia,
別に私は どっちが徽章を
持っていくんでもかまわねえし―
so I'll sell it to the highest bidder.
高いほうに 高く売りつけるさ
I think I like that personality of yours.
いい性格だわ 嫌いじゃない
So how much did this young man bid?
それで そちらのお兄さんは
いくらつけたの？
I'm putting up this metia.
俺が出すのは このミーティアだ
It's a rare item, probably the only
one of its kind in this world.
たぶん 世界に１個しかない
レアアイテム
That muscleman tells me it's worth
no less than twenty holy coins.
そこの筋肉爺さんの話じゃ―
聖金貨で20枚は下らないって
お墨付きだぜ
ミーティア　フッ
A metia...
実は私も 依頼主から ある程度
余分なお金を渡されているの
As it happens, the client sent me
with some extra funds.
少しの上乗せも考える意味でね
Just so I'd be prepared to sweeten the deal.
The client? So you're here as a proxy?
依頼主ってことは エルザさんも
頼まれただけってことか
That's right. The client is the one who wants it.
そうなるわね
欲しがってるのは依頼主のほう
Would you happen to be in the same business?
あなた ひょっとしてご同業？
Being in the same business as me would mean being unemployed!
俺と同業ってことは
無職ってことになるぜ
So this unemployed guy has named a price
that puts him far in the lead.
（フェルト）
…で その無職のお兄ちゃんは
飛び出るような値段をつけた
あんたの飼い主は どんぐらいの
値段がつけられるんだい？
What price is your master putting on it?
（ロム爺）
うーん 20枚ちょうど
Twenty exactly.
These are all the holy coins
my employer sent me with.
私が 依頼主から渡されている
聖金貨は これで全部
Is it not quite enough?
少し厳しいかしら
You're a man!
Don't make such a pathetic face!
男のくせに そんな
みっともない顔するもんじゃない
お前さんのミーティアは―
And I told you that your metia is worth no less than twenty.
聖金貨20枚は下らんと
言ったはずじゃ
As I see it, victory in this
deal is leaning toward the boy.
わしの見立てじゃ
この交渉は この小僧に傾く
お前さんと雇い主には悪いが―
Sorry for you and your employer,
but you'd better bag up those coins and leave.
その金貨は袋に戻して
帰ることじゃな
Hell yeah!
っしゃー！
Wh-What? What's wrong with
a little victory pose? I'm psyched!
（スバル）
な… なんだよ
いいだろ 別にガッツポーズぐらい
うれしかったんだよ
No one said anything.
（フェルト）
別に何も言ってねえだろ
存分に はしゃげよ
Go as crazy as you want.
I don't care as long as I get my profit.
私は もうかればそれでいいし
Sorry, Elsa-san.
You'll probably get in trouble, huh?
（スバル）
ああ 悪いなエルザさん
たぶん 怒られたりしちまうよな
It's fine.
しかたのない話よ
It's my employer's fault for trying to underpay.
雇い主が 支払いを
少なく済まそうなんて―
考えなのが悪いのだし
Well, this deal ended in
disappointment for me,
それじゃあ 交渉は
残念な結果だったけれど―
私は これで失礼するわね
but I'll be taking my leave now.
（エルザ）
そういえば あなたは
その徽章を手に入れてどうするの？
By the way, what do you intend
to do with that insignia?
Oh, I'm going to find its
owner and return it to her.
ああ 元の持ち主捜して返すんだよ
Oh...
なんだ 関係者なのね
So you're with them.
Wh-What?
なっ 何を…
（フェルト）バカ 死ぬ気か？
Do you want to die, moron!?
（エルザ）
あら よけられてしまったわね
Oh, my. You dodged my strike.
うわおーっ！
This is my first battle to the death with a giant!
巨人族と殺し合うのは 初めてよ
Quiet, little girl! I'll grind you up
and feed you to the rats!
ぬかせ小娘 ひき肉にして
大ネズミのエサにしてやるわ！
This isn't good!
ヤバイ
Don't worry. There's no way
Old Man Rom will lose.
大丈夫だ ロム爺が
やられるはずがねえ
Take this!
（ロム爺）くらえー！
Old Man Rom!
ロム爺！
Damn it!
クソッ…
Oh, I almost forgot.
（エルザ）
言い忘れていたけど…
I can at least take you with me!
せめて相打ちに…
Thank you for the milk.
ミルク ごちそうさまでした
I'll return this to you.
これは お返しするわね
You bitch... How dare you?
てめえ… よくも
やってくれやがったな
あら あなたのほうが
勇気があるのね
Oh? It seems you have more courage
than your friend there.
But if you resist,
you might very well get hurt.
だけど手向かうと 痛い思いを
するかもしれないのだけれど
You'll kill me even if I don't fight back,
反撃しなくても殺す気だろうが
この クソ異常者が！
you psychopath!
動かれると 手元が
狂うかもしれないの
If you move around, my hands might slip.
I'm quite rough at handling blades, you see.
私 刃物の扱いが雑だから
Sorry you got caught up in this.
悪かったな 巻き込んじまって
I-I...
（スバル）俺は…
Blessing of the Wind?
（エルザ）風の加護
How wonderful.
I see you are loved by the world.
ステキ 世界に愛されているのね
I envy you!
あなた 妬ましい
The old man and girl have fallen,
yet you remain still.
おじいさんと女の子は倒れ
なのに あなたは動かない
Have you given up?
諦めてしまったの？
クッ… クッソー
D-Damn it...
Oh, you finally stood up.
ああ やっと立つのね
遅いし つまらないけど―
It's less fun since you took
so long, but still, not bad.
悪くはない
（エルザ）
でも 全然ダメ
見たまま素人で 動きは雑
It's meaningless, though.
You're clearly a novice,
and your movements are rough.
You have no blessings or techniques.
加護もなければ 技術もなく―
I was hoping I could squeeze some wisdom out of you, but you lack even that.
せめて 知恵は絞れるかと思えば
それもなし
Shut up! I still have my pride!
（スバル）
うっせえな 意地があるんだよ
After you put me through all this...
こんだけ やられたらな！
I will acknowledge that you have extraordinary determination.
飛び抜けた気骨だけは
認めてあげる
If only you could've shown that sooner,
それが
もっと早くできていれば―
things might have gone differently for these two.
この子たちも 少しは
違ったかもしれないけど
終わりにするとしましょう
I think it's time to end this.
天使に会わせてあげるわ
I'll send you to meet the angels.
おらーっ！
Oh, my. I certainly felt that one.
（エルザ）
ああ 今のは… とても感じたわ
驚いた？ すれ違いざまに
お腹を開いたのよ
Are you surprised?
I opened up your belly
when we passed by one another.
This is the one thing I excel at.
これだけは 私 得意なの
ああ やっぱり
I knew it...
Your guts have such a lovely color!
あなたの腸(はらわた)は―
とてもきれいな色をしていると
思ったの
It hurts... It hurts... It hurts...
（スバル）
痛い 痛い 痛い 痛い…
It hurts... It hurts... It...
Does it hurt? Are you suffering? In pain?
（エルザ）
痛い？ 苦しい？
辛い？ 悲しい？
死んでしまいたい？
It doesn't hurt?
Sad? Do you want to die?
Die?
（スバル）死ぬ？
Am I dead?
（スバル）
死んだのか まだ生きてる
いつ死ぬ？ いつ死ぬ？
I'm still alive?
When will I die?
When will I die!?
ゆっくり ゆっくり ゆっくり…
I'm scared. I'm scared. I'm scared.
Slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly...
I'm scared! I'm scared! I'm scared!
（エルザ）ゆっくり ゆっくり…
（スバル）怖い怖い怖い…
（エルザ）ゆっくり そう
（スバル）死ぬ死ぬ死ぬ…
I'm gonna die! I'm gonna die! I'm gonna die!
（エルザ）ゆっくりと熱が失われて
（スバル）死ぬ死ぬ死ぬ…
Yes, you're slowly losing body heat...
I'm gonna die! I'm gonna die! I'm gonna die!
（スバル）
死ぬ 死ぬ ハア ハア…
I'm gonna die!
You're slowly growing cold...
（エルザ）
ゆっくりと冷たくなっていって…
Oh, I'm dead.
（スバル）あ… 死んだ
What's the matter, bud?
（カドモン）
どうしたよ 兄ちゃん
急にほうけたツラして
You look like you saw a ghost.
Hey, buddy. You okay?
おい 兄ちゃん
大丈夫か？
I have no idea what's going on anymore...
もう わけ分かんねえ
You okay there, bud?
大丈夫か 兄ちゃん
金はいらねえ
Forget about the money.
Here, just take these.
とりあえず ほれ
Hey, wait...
ちょっ… 待って
Wait! Please, wait!
待ってくれ
頼む 待って！
待ってくれ サテラー！
Wait!
Satella!
Please don't ignore me!
無視しないでくれ
I guess it's my fault for going off on my own and not listening to you!
いなくなったのも―
言うこと
聞かなかったのも―
俺が悪かった
But I was desperate!
でも 俺も
必死だったんだ
あれから
遠い村にも行ったんだ
I went back to the loot house after that,
but I couldn't find you...
けど 会えなくて…
I'm sorry for only thinking of myself.
自分のことばっかでごめん
でも 無事でよかった
But I'm glad you're all right, Satella.
サテラ
What's your problem?
あなた
どういうつもり？
I don't know who you are,
誰だか知らないけど―
but calling me by the name of the Witch of Envy...
人を嫉妬の魔女の
名前で呼んで―
What is your problem!?
どういうつもりなの！
The  End of the   Beginning and
the  Beginning of the   End